<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>meteoroid | Gabriel Szász</title>
    <link>https://szasz.space/tags/meteoroid/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://szasz.space/tags/meteoroid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>meteoroid</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020 Gabriel Szász</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 17:34:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://szasz.space/img/gszasz-profile.png</url>
      <title>meteoroid</title>
      <link>https://szasz.space/tags/meteoroid/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Meteor Terminology Right</title>
      <link>https://szasz.space/post/getting-the-meteor-terminology-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 17:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://szasz.space/post/getting-the-meteor-terminology-right/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people know that words are just labels and when it comes to communication.  We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t insist on using the right words, while the context is self-evident to everybody.  The problem arises when people swap similar words with entirely different meaning, like in the following examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;astronomy – astrology&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;physicist – physician&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;meteorology – metrology&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;scientometry – Scientology&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;psychologist – psychopath&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can lead to confusion and chain of misunderstandings.  While words themselves do not matter, they should remain stable and well-defined for the sake of communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media share information with the extensive amount of people.  Swapping of the similar words in the media can lead to mass confusion.  It&amp;rsquo;s surely not hard to imagine that saying, e.g., &lt;em&gt;psychopath&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;psychologist&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Scientologist&lt;/em&gt; instead of &lt;em&gt;scientometrist&lt;/em&gt; could have very unpleasant consequences.  One would expect that media put extensive effort to get the terminology right, but it turns out it&amp;rsquo;s not the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general public is aware that the Earth is being exposed to the collisions with interplanetary medium.  An even small possibility of such a collision results in large headlines in the media.  Unfortunately, media severely fail very when it comes to astronomy terms.  It&amp;rsquo;s mind-blowing to realize that someone who is capable of learning the difference between &lt;em&gt;physicist&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;physician&lt;/em&gt; is still able to mess up meteoroid with meteor or meteorite&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meteoroid is a small piece of debris flying in space.&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s usually a grain of sand or dust.  The largest meteoroids have 1 meter in diameter.  Everything from 1 meter to hundreds of kilometres in diameter is already being called asteroid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meteor&lt;/em&gt; is a &lt;em&gt;phenomenon&lt;/em&gt; observed when a physical body from outer space is flying through Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere in high velocity.  The light is emitted by tube of excited and ionized air along the trajectory.  Vast majority of meteors are caused by meteoroids or asteroids; nevertheless, it could be also any piece of artificial space debris.  Meteors are also being commonly called &lt;em&gt;shooting stars&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meteorite&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;a piece of rock found on the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface&lt;/em&gt; that happens to be the fragment of a meteoroid or an asteroid.  As this fragment survived passage through the atmosphere, meteorite&amp;rsquo;s structure differs from the original material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three terms are like an &lt;em&gt;employer&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;employment&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;employee&lt;/em&gt; – although they are very similar and undoubtedly related words, they are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mutually interchangeable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
