<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts | Gabriel Szász</title><link>https://szasz.space/post/</link><atom:link href="https://szasz.space/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Posts</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2020 Gabriel Szász</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 17:34:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://szasz.space/img/gszasz-profile.png</url><title>Posts</title><link>https://szasz.space/post/</link></image><item><title>Getting the Meteor Terminology Right</title><link>https://szasz.space/post/getting-the-meteor-terminology-right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 17:34:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://szasz.space/post/getting-the-meteor-terminology-right/</guid><description>&lt;p>Most people know that words are just labels and when it comes to communication. We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t insist on using the right words, while the context is self-evident to everybody. The problem arises when people swap similar words with entirely different meaning, like in the following examples.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>astronomy – astrology&lt;/em>,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>physicist – physician&lt;/em>,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>meteorology – metrology&lt;/em>,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>scientometry – Scientology&lt;/em>,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>psychologist – psychopath&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This can lead to confusion and chain of misunderstandings. While words themselves do not matter, they should remain stable and well-defined for the sake of communication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Media share information with the extensive amount of people. Swapping of the similar words in the media can lead to mass confusion. It&amp;rsquo;s surely not hard to imagine that saying, e.g., &lt;em>psychopath&lt;/em> instead of &lt;em>psychologist&lt;/em>, or &lt;em>Scientologist&lt;/em> instead of &lt;em>scientometrist&lt;/em> could have very unpleasant consequences. One would expect that media put extensive effort to get the terminology right, but it turns out it&amp;rsquo;s not the case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The general public is aware that the Earth is being exposed to the collisions with interplanetary medium. An even small possibility of such a collision results in large headlines in the media. Unfortunately, media severely fail very when it comes to astronomy terms. It&amp;rsquo;s mind-blowing to realize that someone who is capable of learning the difference between &lt;em>physicist&lt;/em> and &lt;em>physician&lt;/em> is still able to mess up meteoroid with meteor or meteorite&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Meteoroid is a small piece of debris flying in space.&lt;/em> It&amp;rsquo;s usually a grain of sand or dust. The largest meteoroids have 1 meter in diameter. Everything from 1 meter to hundreds of kilometres in diameter is already being called asteroid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Meteor&lt;/em> is a &lt;em>phenomenon&lt;/em> observed when a physical body from outer space is flying through Earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere in high velocity. The light is emitted by tube of excited and ionized air along the trajectory. Vast majority of meteors are caused by meteoroids or asteroids; nevertheless, it could be also any piece of artificial space debris. Meteors are also being commonly called &lt;em>shooting stars&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Meteorite&lt;/em> is &lt;em>a piece of rock found on the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface&lt;/em> that happens to be the fragment of a meteoroid or an asteroid. As this fragment survived passage through the atmosphere, meteorite&amp;rsquo;s structure differs from the original material.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>These three terms are like an &lt;em>employer&lt;/em>, &lt;em>employment&lt;/em>, and &lt;em>employee&lt;/em> – although they are very similar and undoubtedly related words, they are &lt;em>not&lt;/em> mutually interchangeable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Four Thousand Weeks</title><link>https://szasz.space/post/four-thousand-weeks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 23:12:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://szasz.space/post/four-thousand-weeks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our lifespan is about four thousand weeks long. Every single week we receive an opportunity to learn something new. It would be a foolish idea to waste it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Four thousand weeks&amp;hellip; The voice of the endless fear inside us is crying out loud: &amp;ldquo;It cannot be!&amp;rdquo; The bare truth is that period of 4,000 weeks translates into 76.7 years - the average human lifespan. Maths was always reaching far beyond the dream bubbles of our own emotions, holding the key to the absolute truth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The truth can be very depressing, especially for those who have already wasted too much time. We tend to spend whole weeks of our life by re-evaluating our past or fantasizing about the future. We are dreaming our lives rather than living them. Time flies, and it seems that nothing can fulfill our expectations. Such a life is full of injustice, regret, despair and&amp;hellip; fear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not everyone is lucky enough to live all four thousand weeks. We do not know what will happen to us tomorrow. There is maybe no time to regret, no time to plan, no time to be afraid. The only time that left is the time for&amp;hellip; life. Time for enjoying the fresh air with every breath, feeling the gentle touch of the morning breeze, watching a dewdrop sliding down the leaf, touching soft carpet of grass with your bare feet&amp;hellip; Real happiness is hidden in the present time, somewhere between seconds of our lives. It is there if you want it to be. If you let happiness just pass around, seconds will become minutes, minutes will become days and days will become weeks&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Four thousand weeks&amp;hellip; what one can do in such a time span? Some people can do nothing, but waiting for death&amp;hellip; Some people can save the world. We have freedom of choice, all of us.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When you enjoy every single second of your life, four thousand weeks seem like eternity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>